# **DAVID TESNO**

Web Developer

(919) 259-2321

adavidtesno@gmail.com

Takoma Park, MD 20912

Portfolio: <a href="http://davidtesno.com/">http://davidtesno.com/</a>



### **OVERVIEW**

Tech-savvy Web Developer with solid front-end skills. Thorough comprehension of complex HTML, CSS, and JavaScript programming languages to create custom webpages and web apps. Versed at planning, designing, and implementing website structure and navigation layouts. Integrates knowledge of visual arts to develop functional, creative, immersive, custom-made web products and services. Former Executive Chef with strong leadership and planning experience.

## **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

HTML/Semantic Markup — CSS — Beginner Javascript — Flexbox

Bootstrap - Responsive Design - CSS Grid - Github

Email Design — Production & Deployment — Clean Code Practices

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2017 - 2020

#### Quantitative Manager | Main Event Caterers | Arlington, VA

Managed back-end data for a large platform software called CaterXpert. Created, updated, and removed system data utilized by all departments in the company including inventory data, sales, ordering, production, and reporting.

Quantified sales estimates for multiple business units to match company guidelines; edited sales summaries and approved estimates for production or rejected estimates if quants were inaccurate, had errors, or did not meet the minimum variance.

2015 – 2017 | Resident Chef | Sur La Table | Arlington, VA

2015 – 2015 | Chef Instructor | Sur La Table | Alexandria, VA

2010 – 2014 | Executive Chef | Gaylord National Hotel | National Harbor, MD

## **EDUCATION**

The Complete Web Developer in 2021: Zero to Mastery Certificate Udemy | 2021

Associates Degree in Culinary Arts Culinary Institute of America | Hyde Park, NY | June 1995

#### **SKILLS**

- Team Management
- Planning & Execution
- Leadership
- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Decision Making

#### **HONORS**

2013 Marriot Gaylord National Q3 Excellence in Leadership Award

2012 Gaylord National Q1
Excellence in Leadership Runnerup Award